Guide to the Michael Lerner Collection on MAD Magazine research, 1951-2005 SPEC.CGA.MLM
Ohio State University Libraries Special Collections
- Articles, 1951-2005
  - Articles in Publications, 1951-2000
    - Cartoonist Profiles, "Famous Interviewer", December 1972 (Box MLM 4, Item 17)
      Paul Coker article with illustrations
    - Cartoonist Profiles, "World War II Cartoons", May 1975 (Box MLM 4, Item 18)
      Jack Davis illustration on cover
    - Cartoonist Profiles, "Alfred E. Neuman Portrait Painter", June 1975 (Box MLM 4, Item 19)
      Norman Mingo illustration of William Gaines on cover with Mingo interview
    - Cartoonist Profiles, "MAD T- Shirt Profiles", December 1975 (Box MLM 4, Item 20)
      MAD artists draw themselves
    - Cartoonist Profiles, "Comic Command Performance", March 1976 (Box MLM 4, Item 21)
      Dave Berg redraws some earlier work from the 1940s
    - Cartoonist Profiles, "MAD Kong", June 1977 (Box MLM 5, Item 1)
      Harry North interview with illustration
    - Cartoonist Profiles, March 1981 (Box MLM 5, Item 2)
      Cartoon Museum tribute to the artists and writers of MAD
    - Cartoonist Profiles, December 1981 (Box MLM 5, Item 3)
      Don Martin interview (Part 1 of 2)
    - Cartoonist Profiles, March 1982 (Box MLM 5, Box 4)
      Don Martin interview (Part 2 of 2)
    - Cartoonist Profiles, "Don Edwing MAD's Biz-artist", March 1984 (Box MLM 5, Item 5)
      Interview
    - Cartoonist Profiles, "MAD", Undated (Box MLM 5, Item 6)
      Article about MAD submissions policy featuring Nick Meglin
    - Cartoonist Profiles, "The 1989 MAD Trip", September 1990 (Box MLM 5, Item 7)
      Article written by John Ficcarra regarding the 1989 MAD trip to Germany
    - Cartoonist Profiles, "Don Martin and 'The Nutheads'", December 1990 (Box MLM 5, Item 8)
      Don Martin interviewed about his proposed 'Nutheads' comic strip
    - Cartoonist Profiles, "Sergio Aragones and the Art of Pantomine Cartooning", March 1993 (Box MLM 5, Item 9)
      An overview of the creative process of Sergio Aragones with illustration. Part 1 of 2
    - Cartoonist Profiles, "100 Issues, 8360 Pages, 25th Anniversary", December 1993 (Box MLM 5, Item 10)
    - Cavalier, "Super-hero as Schlemiel", September 1965 (Box MLM 5, Item 11)
      Article about superhero comics with brief mention of MAD
    - Christian Century, "The MAD Morality: An Expose", December 27, 1967 (Box MLM 5, Item 12)
      Vernard Eller article which later became a book. Follow-up letter to the editor in February 28, 1968 issue
    - Cinefantastique, "Tales from the Crypt", January 1990 (Box MLM 5, Item 13)
      "Tales from the Crypt" TV show article with William Gaines sidebar interview
    - Cleveland Magazine, October 1990 (Box MLM 6, Item 1)
      Article about local radio station with brief mention of MAD
    - Collectible Toys & Values, July 1992 (Box MLM 6, Item 2)
      Scope and Contents note
      Information on "Screwball: The MAD MAD Game" on page 56
    - Collecting Figures, "No Worries with MAD Collectibles", March 1995 (Box MLM 6, Item 3)
      Article about MAD collectibles with color photos
    - Collector Magazine, "MAD in LA", September 1995 (Box MLM 6, Item 4)
      Featured article about Sotheby's MAD art auction in NYC
    - Collector's Showcase, "Mad about mAD: Sotheby's to Sell Original Artwork", October/ November 1995 (Box MLM 6, Item 5)
      Article with color illustrations about upcoming Sotheby's MAD art auction
    - Collector's Showcase, "MAD Collectibles", July/ August 1997 (Box MLM 6, Item 6)
      Article and Alfred E. Newman mask on cover
    - Columbia Journalism Review, "Campaign '88: Does TV Deserve a Medal?", January/ February 1989 (Box MLM 6, Item 7)
      Alfred E. Newman on cover
    - Columbus Dispatch Television Plus, "What, Me Worry?", Undated (Box MLM 6, Item 8)
      Title on cover regarding an article on Chris Elliott
    - Comedy, "Help! I'm a Prisoner of the Future", Summer 1980 (Box MLM 6, Item 9)
      Article about "Help" magazine with interviews with H. Kurtzman, G. Steinam, J. Warren
    - Comic Book Marketplace, No. 2, 1991 (Box MLM 6, Item 10)
    - Comic Book Marketplace, No. 4, 1991 (Box MLM 6, Item 11)
    - Comic Book Marketplace, No. 5, 1991 (Box MLM 6, Item 12)
    - Comic Book Marketplace, No. 16, August 1992 (Box MLM 6, Item 13)
      William Gaines tribute articles (including a reprint of the Comic Book Guide interview from 1978)
    - Comic Book Marketplace, No. 18, October 1992 (Box MLM 6, Item 14)
    - Comic Book Marketplace, No. 19, November 1992 (Box MLM 6, Item 15)
    - Comics Buyer's Guide, "Don Martin leaves 'MAD' for 'Cracked'", November 13, 1987 (Box MLM 6, Item 16)
      Cover story plus artwork
    - Comic Buyer's Guide, "Don Martin replies to MAD", December 4, 1987 (Box MLM 7, Item 1)
      Article in which Don and Norma Martin angrily reply to the Comics Buyer's Guide and USA Today (11/10/1987) stories detailing his split from MAD
    - Comics Buyer's Guide "Harvey Kurtzman Dies, Creator of MAD", March 19, 1993 (Box MLM 24, Item 3)
      Editorial and article trubute.
    - Comics Buyer's Guide, April 2, 1993 (Box MLM 24, Item 4)
      Issue devoted to Harvey Kurtzman with various tributes from throughout the industry.
    - Comics Buyer's Guide, January 15, 1993 (Box MLM 24, Item 5)
    - Comics Buyer's Guide, February 6, 1998 (Box MLM 24, Item 6)
      Sergio Aragone's illustration on cover.
    - Comics Buyer's Guide, March 20, 1998 (Box MLM 24, Item 7)
      Spy vs. Spy Creator Antonio Prohias dies, page 8.
    - Comics Collector, Winter 1985 (Box MLM 7, Item 2)
    - Comics Features, No. 17, June 1981 (Box MLM 7, Item 3)
    - Comics Interview, No. 12, 1984 (Box MLM 7, Item 4)
    - Comics Interview, No. 100, 1991 (Box MLM 7, Item 5)
    - The Comics Journal, December 1979 (Box MLM 7, Item 6)
      Don Martin/ Captain Klutz T-shirt advertisement
    - The Comics Journal, Winter Special, 1980 (Box MLM 7, Item 7)
    - The Comics Journal, "The Life, Death and Resurrection of EC Comics", November 1980 (Box MLM 7, Item 8)
    - The Comics Journal, August 1981 (Box MLM 7, Item 9)
    - The Comics Journal, "Harvey Kurtzman", October 1981 (Box MLM 7, Item 10)
      In-depth Harvey Kurtzman interview
    - The Comics Journal, "Wally Wood Dead at 54", December 1981 (Box MLM 7, Item 11)
      Wally Wood career review
    - The Comics Journal, "There are Good Guys and Bad Guys, January 1982 (Box MLM 7, Item 12)
      Memories of Wally Wood by Bob Stewart
    - The Comics Journal, "Censorship in Comics", November 1982 (Box MLM 7, Item 13)
      William Gaines is featured at a panel discussion at the June 11 Dallas Fantasy Fair
    - The Comics Journal, "William Gaines", May 1983 (Box MLM 7, Item 14)
      In-depth William Gaines interview
    - The Comics Journal, July 1984 (Box MLM 8, Item 1)
      Harvey Kurtzman interview from 1982 Creation Con
    - The Comics Journal, "The Mystery Artist", March 1985 (Box MLM 8, Item 2)
      Howard Nostrand interview with EC Comics and MAD references
    - The Comics Journal, July 1985 (Box MLM 8, Item 3)
      Follow-up interviews with Harvey Kurtzman and William Gaines
    - The Comics Journal, "Around the World in 80,000 Gags", April 1989 (Box MLM 8, Item 4)
      Sergio Aragones interviewed in feature article
    - The Comics Journal, "Take Five", June 1991 (Box MLM 8, Item 5)
      Arnold Roth interview featuring information about MAD, Kurtzman, Humbug, Trump, and Help magazine
    - The Comics Journal, "William Gaines Dead at 70", July 1992 (Box MLM 8, Item 6)
      Gaines obituary and tribute
    - The Comics Journal, "Harvey Kurtzman Issue", October 1992 (Box MLM 8, Item 7)
      Issue devoted totally to Kurtzman, including old and new interviews, timeline, tributes, reprints. This issue also includes Jack Davis interview and cover illustration
    - The Comics Journal, "Harvey Kurtzman, 1924-1993: A Tribute", March 1993 (Box MLM 8, Item 8)
      Harvey Kurtzman bio snf tribute from various comic book artists and writers
    - The Comics Journal, "EC Issue", May 1995 (Box MLM 8, Item 9)
      Interviews with Al Feldstein, Will Elder, and George Evans with illustrations
    - The Comics Journal, "Wally Wood: His Life and Art", July 1997 (Box MLM 8, Item 10)
      Cover and feature article on Wally Wood
    - The Comics Journal, July 2000 (Box MLM 8, Item 11)
      Parody of MAD magazine, Alfred E. Neuman on cover
    - Comics Scene, "Mad About the Boy", December 1990 (Box MLM 8, Item 12)
      Harvey Kurtzman interview
    - Comics Scene, "Reluctant Legend: William Gaines", October 1991 (Box MLM 9, Item 1)
      Interview with Gaines
    - Comics Scene, "In Rememberance of William M. Gaines", October 1992 (Box MLM 9, Item 2)
      One page tribute to Gaines with photos
    - Comics Scene, "Harvey Kurtzman", June 1993 (Box MLM 9, Item 3)
      One page tribute to Harvey Kurtzman
    - Comics Scene, "Diary of a MAD Man"; "Last Words", July 1993 (Box MLM 9, Item 4)
      Article and interview with Will Elder; Part two of a final interview with William Gaines
    - Comics Scene, "Memories Most MAD", July 1993 (Box MLM 9, Item 5)
      A final interview with Harvey Kurtzman
    - Comic Shop News, April 23, 1997 (Box MLM 9, Item 6)
    - Consumer Reports, "Board Games Kids Liked Best", November 1981 (Box MLM 9, Item 7)
      Article about board games featuring the MAD game
    - Contact, November 1993 (Box MLM 9, Item 8)
      Jack Davis cover illustration with Alfred E. Neuman cameo
    - Connoisseur, July 1988 (Box MLM 9, Item 9)
    - The Contentious Journal, June 1983 (Box MLM 9, Item 10)
      Parody Issue
    - Coronet, "It's Just Plain MAD", May 1960 (Box MLM 9, Item 11)
      Behind the scenes at MAD with art reproductions
    - Discover, "Who's Watching You?", March 1988 (Box MLM 9, Item 12)
      Prohias' Spy vs. Spy illustration used on cover and in non-related story
    - Discover, November 1988 (Box MLM 9, Item 13)
    - Discoveries, December 1990 (Box MLM 24, Item 8)
      Article on Michael Lerner's MAD record listing, page 10.
    - Drag Racer, "Alfred E. Neuman on Drag Racing", January 1999 (Box MLM 9, Item 14)
      Alfred E. Neuman on race car
    - Drag Racing Monthly, May 1998 (Box MLM 9, Item 15)
      Alfred E. Neuman race car
    - Drag Racing Monthly, February 1999 (Box MLM 9, Item 16)
    - Dynamite! (Scholastic), "A Visit to the MADhouse", Janaury 1974 (Box MLM 9, Item 17)
      Alfred E. Neuman cover and article
    - Dynamite! (Scholastic), "MAD About the Boy" The Strange Story of Alfred E. Neuman", January 1976 (Box MLM 9, Item 18)
      Article about the originsl of Alfred E. Neuman
    - Dynamite! (Scholastic), "Happy Birthday, MAD" (2 copies), April 1978 (Box MLM 9, Item 19-20)
      Article about the 25th Anniversary of MAD
    - Dynamite! (Scholastic), October 1978 (Box MLM 9, Item 21)
      Sam Viviano cover illustration
    - Editor & Publisher, "Eleven Cartoonists Receive NCS Honors", June 4, 1988 (Box MLM 10, Item 1)
      Mort Drucker wins annual Reuben award
    - Editor & Publisher, "Two Divergent But Important Influences: Thomas Nast and MAD", June 24, 1989 (Box MLM 10, Item 2)
      MAD discussed at Editorial Cartoonists meeting
    - Editor & Publisher, "MAD Veteran Doing a Syndicated Comic", January 16, 1993 (Box MLM 10, Item 3)
      Brief article about plans to syndicate the "Roger Kaputnik" Dave Berg strip to newspapers; cartoon featured
    - English Journal, "MAD Magazine in the Remedial English Class", February 1970 (Box MLM 10, Item 4)
      Discusses using MAD as a learning tool
    - English Journal, "Don't Get Mad or Go Mad: Use MAD", March 1989 (Box MLM 10, Item 5)
      How to use MAD as a teaching tool in school
    - Entertainment Weekly, "The Man Who Drove America MAD", June 19, 1992 (Box MLM 10, Item 7)
      Gaines tribute featuring Al Jaffee fold-in
    - Entertainment Weekly, "Batlash", July 31, 1992 (Box MLM 10, Item 8)
      Jack Davis cartoon, page 33
    - Entertainment Weekly, "Decked Out", September 4, 1992 (Box MLM 10, Item 9)
      Article about the latest trading cards, photo of a MAD card (series 1) featured along with other cards
    - Entertainment Weekly, "Harvey Kurtzman: MAD Genius", March 5, 1993 (Box MLM 10, Item 10)
      Kurtzman obituary and tribute
    - Entertainment Weekly, "Still MAD after all These Years", Ocotber 6, 1995 (Box MLM 10, Item 11)
      Full page homage to MAD and color photo of the first issue and Alfred E. Neuman
    - Entertainment Weekly, "Still MAD after all These Years", Undated (Box MLM 10, Item 11)
    - Entertainment Weekly, October 13, 1995 (Box MLM 10, Item 12)
      MAD TV mentioned in 'Hot Sheet' column; Negative review of MAD TV premier episode with Spy vs. Spy character shown
    - Entertainment Weekly, "Can Roseanne Save Sketch Comedy?", April 12, 1996 (Box MLM 10, Item 13)
      Article discusses new Rosanne comedy show on Fox that is temporarily replacing MAD TV
    - Entertainment Weekly, "What, Him Worry?", December 19, 1997 (Box MLM 10, Item 14)
      NBC's Warren Littlefield as Alfred E. Neuman caricature
    - Entertainment Weekly, "We're Not 'MAD'", March 27, 1998 (Box MLM 10, Item 15)
      MAD magazine parody issue of Entertainment Weekly
    - Entertainment Weekly, July 9, 1999 (Box MLM 10, Item 16)
    - Entertainment Weekly, August 20-27, 1999 (Box MLM 10, Item 17)
    - Entertainment Weekly, January 21-28, 2000 (Box MLM 10, Item 18)
    - Esquire, "Special Sophistication Issue", August 1964 (Box MLM 24, Item 1)
      "BAD"- a MAD parody.
    - Esquire, September 1990 (Box MLM 11, Item 1)
      Alfred E. Neuman illustration in feature about look-a-likes
    - Esquire, "What, Me Worry?", June 1992 (Box MLM 11, Item 2)
      Cover illustration by Richard Williams of George (H.W.) Bush as Alfred E. Neuman
    - Fact, "Don't Go Away, MAD", November/ December 1965 (Box MLM 11, Item 3)
      MAD versus the John Birch Society
    - Fanfare, "Al Feldstein 'A Time for Panic'", April 1977 (Box MLM 11, Item 4)
      Article with reprinted illustrations from various MAD parodies of horror movies; this issue also has a letter and photograph from the MAD editors
    - Fanfare, Winter 1978 (Box MLM 11, Item 5)
    - Fanfare, "Elder Goes Commerical", Spring 1980 (Box MLM 11, Item 6)
      Will Elder advertising work reviewed with examples
    - Fanfare, "Record Album Art of Jack Davis", Summer 1983 (Box MLM 11, Item 7)
      Shows examples of Davis' album artwork
    - Folio's Publishing News, "MAD to Change Format When Hell Freezes", June 15, 1991 (Box MLM 25, Item 2)
      General article featuring illustration of Gaines, Ficarra, and Meglin by Mort Drucker.
    - Forbes, "The Secret is in the Repackaging", June 15, 1987 (Box MLM 11, Item 8)
      Discusses MAD's special issues and books
    - Filmmakers Newsletter, December 1977 (Box MLM 11, Item 9)
    - Game, Undated (Box MLM 11, Item 10)
      Back cover: advertisement for MAD Silver Jubliee issue
    - Gauntlet, "An Interview with William M. Gaines", January 1992 (Box MLM 11, Item 11)
      Possible last full inteview with Gaines before his death in June 1992
    - Gauntlet, "Death of a MAD- Man", October 1992 (Box MLM 11, Item 12)
      Tribute article about William M. Gaines
    - Harvard Lampoon, Undated (Box MLM 12, Item 1)
    - Heavy Metal, "Dossier", February 1985 (Box MLM 12, Item 2)
      Jack Davis information
    - Hits Magazine, August 1989 (Box MLM 12, Item 3)
      Cover article about Mark Cohen MAD exhibit at the Artspace Gallery and Studio Complex in Raleigh, NC, with photos
    - Honk, "The MAD World of Don Martin", November 1986 (Box MLM 12, Item 4)
      Don Martin interview
    - How, "Working MAD", Juky/ August 1988 (Box MLM 12, Item 5)
      Article describing Al Jaffee "Fold-in" techniques
    - The Hurried Child, David Elkind, 1988 (Box MLM 12, Item 6)
      page 81 of book mentions MAD magazine
    - Hustler, "William Gaines", February 1981 (Box MLM 12, Item 7)
      Article by Frank Jacobs about Gaines and MAD
    - Hustler, September 1995 (Box MLM 12, Item 8)
      X-rated spoof of typical MAD features
    - Hyena, 1993 (Box MLM 12, Item 9)
      EC Comics inspired story
    - ie (Information Entertainment), "What, Me Forty?", Spring 1992 (Box MLM 12, Item 10)
      Article about "Completely MAD" book
    - ie (Information Entertainment), "Going, Going...MAD"; "How MAD Can You Get???", November 1992 (Box MLM 12, Item 11)
      Article about October 20, 1992 Sotheby's auction; MAD trivia contest
    - Image (San Francisco Examiner insert), "It's a M-A-D World!", April 18, 1993 (Box MLM 12, Item 12)
      Art Spiegelman's "Lead Pipe Sunday" Harvey Kurtzman, Bill Griffith and Tom Tomorrow
    - Inklings, Spring 1997 (Box MLM 13, Item 1)
    - Inklings, "King Kong Gets Heimlich Maneuver: Jack Davis donates his MAD Magazine art" (2copies), Summer 1997 (Box MLM 13, Item 2-3)
      Jack Davis cover illustration; donates his original art to the International Museum of Cartoon Art
    - Inks, "William Gaines and the Battle over EC Comics", February 1996 (Box MLM 13, Item 5)
      Article by Amy Kiste Nyberg; cover illustration by Mort Drucker
    - Inquirer Magazine (The Philadelphia Inquirer insert), "What, Me Worry?", July 20, 1997 (Box MLM 13, Item 6)
      Time Warner pushes MAD to the cutting edge; Alfred E. Neuman caricature on cover
    - The Inside Collector, October 1990 (Box MLM 13, Item 7)
    - ISP News, November- December 1991 (Box MLM 25, Item 3)
    - International Club, "It's a mad, mad, mad, mad. mad world", November 1977 (Box MLM 13, Item 8)
      Pages 22-23, classic MAD covers
    - Journal of Communication, "MAD Economics", Winter 1984 (Box MLM 13, Item 9)
    - Kiplinger's, "What, Me Worry?", April 1988 (Box MLM 13, Item 10)
      Headline for the column "Managing Money Q & A"
    - Ladies' Home Journal, "What Parents Don't Know About Comic Books", November 1953 (Box MLM 25, Item 4)
      Werthan comics articles which set the stage for the "Seduction of the Innocent" book.
    - Liberty, March 1955 (Box MLM 13, Item 11)
    - Life, "The Whole Country Goes Supermad", March 11, 1966 (Box MLM 25, Item 5)
      The MAD Show article.
    - Life, May 18, 1953 (Box MLM 25, Item 6)
    - Life, "Helping Hands", June 1986 (Box MLM 25, Item 7)
      4 pages of cartoon characters including Alfred E. Neuman.
    - Life, "Spy vs. Spy", September 1986 (Box MLM 25, Item 8)
      Spy vs. Spy illustration used in article.
    - Life, "MAD Youth", August 1992 (Box MLM 13, Item 12)
      Story by Art Spiegelman who writes about events in his life and how they were influenced by MAD
    - Life, "Almanac", March 1997 (Box MLM 13, Item 13)
      William Gaines, "free-speech advocate" five year anniversary of death
    - Look, "MAD Miracle", March 19, 1968 (Box MLM 25, Item 9)
      Articles discussing the MAd Phenomenon with photographs and illustrations.
    - Look, "Sound of Their Lives", September 20, 1966 (Box MLM 26, Item 1)
      Alfred E. Newman caricature
    - Mediascene, "The MAD World of Jack Davis", November- December 1975 (Box MLM 26, Item 2)
      Background and interview.
    - New York, "How MAD Shapes U.S. Politics", Ocotber 1, 1973 (Box MLM 16, Item 1)
      Feature article about MAD
    - New York Times Magazine, "The MAD Generation", July 31, 1977 (Box MLM 26, Item 3)
      Article about MAD and how it influenced an entire generation of readers
    - News & Observer Weekend, "It's a MAD, MAD, MAD...World", November 6, 1992 (Box MLM 26, Item 4)
      Cover article about Mark Cohen MAD exhibit at the Artspace Gallery and Studio Complex in Raleigh, NC; with illustrations about photographs
    - Newsweek, "Are Comics Horrible?", May 3, 1954 (Box MLM 16, Item 2)
      Article relating to U.S. Senate investigation on comic books
    - Newsweek, "Crazy Like a Fox", August 31, 1959 (Box MLM 16, Item 3)
      Overview of MAD phenomenon
    - Newsweek, "Thunder on the Far Right", December 4, 1961 (Box MLM 16, Item 4)
      Article on right-wing personality, Edwin Walker, who disliked MAD
    - Newsweek, "Who's MAD?", April 9, 1962 (Box MLM 16, Item 5)
      MAD 10th Anniversary article with photographs of Gaines and Feldstein plus cover art from MAD #62
    - Newsweek, "Sing Along with MAD", April 6, 1964 (Box MLM 16, Item 6)
      MAD sued by Irving Berlin
    - Newsweek, "MADcappery", January 24, 1966 (Box MLM 16, Item 7)
      The MAD Show review with image of Alfred E. Newman
    - Newsweek, Spetember 30, 1974 (Box MLM 16, Item 8)
      Editorial cartoon featuring Alfred E. Newman (from the Louisville [KY] Courier Journal)
    - Newsweek, "Still MAD after all these years", April 25, 1983 (Box MLM 16, Item 9)
      MAD Sidebard article in feature about satire and humor magazine
    - Newsweek, February 10, 1986 (Box MLM 16, Item 10)
    - Newsweek, "Acquisition of the Year: MAD Magazine", March 20, 1989 (Box MLM 16, Item 11)
      How MAD will adjust to Time- Warner merger
    - Newsweek, "Completely MAD", December 2, 1991 (Box MLM 16, Item 12)
      Mention of "Completely MAD."
    - Newsweek, "It Takes a Worried Man", May 18, 1992 (Box MLM 16, Item 13)
      Brief article showing the June 1992 Esquire cover featuring George Bush as Alfred E. Neuman.
    - Newsweek, "Humor in Jugular Vein", June 15, 1992 (Box MLM 16, Item 14)
      Gaines tribute.
    - Newsweek, "Transition", March 8, 1993 (Box MLM 16, Item 15)
      Harvey Kurtzman obituary.
    - Newsweek, August 2, 1999 (Box MLM 16, Item 16)
    - Newsweek, January 17, 2000 (Box MLM 16, Item 17)
    - Non- Sports Update, July- September 1992 (Box MLM 16, Item 18)
      MAD Trading cards advertisement.
    - Non- Sport Update, October- December 1992 (Box MLM 16, Item 19)
      Article on the art of Basil Wolverton and MAD trading card advertisement.
    - Nostalgia World, Fall 1982 (Box MLM 16, Item 20)
      Cover features old phorographs of pre-MAD Alfred E. Neuman.
    - Oui, "A Conversation with William Gaines", February 1979 (Box MLM 17, Item 1)
      IN-depth William M. Gaines interview with N. Mingo and D. Martin illustration
    - Overstreet Comic Price Guide, Summer 1993 (Box MLM 17, Item 2)
      Interview with Harvey Kurtzman and Kurtzman illustration on cover
    - Pageant, January 1951 (Box MLM 17, Item 3)
    - Pageant, March 1951 (Box MLM 17, Item 4)
    - Pageant, June 1954 (Box MLM 17, Item 5)
    - Pageant, November 1954 (Box MLM 17, Item 6)
    - Parade, June 9, 1996 (Box MLM 17, Item 7)
      Full color back page advertisement for Franklin Mint "Alfred E. Neuman for President"plate
    - Parents, Ocotber 1953 (Box MLM 17, Item 8)
    - Parents, "Annual Rating of Comic Magazines", August 1954 (Box MLM 17, Item 9)
      MAD and Panic listed as objectionable magazines
    - People, March 4, 1974 (Box MLM 17, Item 10)
    - People, August 28, 1989 (Box MLM 17, Item 11)
      Reference to Alfred E. Neuman in the review of a Beastie Boys album
    - People, April 29, 1991 (Box MLM 17, Item 12)
      "What, Me Worry?" on cover in relation to Kitty Kelly book about Nancy Reagan
    - People, November 18, 1991 (Box MLM 17, Item 13)
      MAD cover #180 shown in review of book "The American Magazine."
    - People, January 13, 1992 (Box MLM 17, Item 14)
      Negative book review of "Completely MAD."
    - People, April 13, 1992 (Box MLM 18, Item 1)
      One line refernce to MAD:"...Dick DeBartolo turns MAD movie parodies," in the movie review for The Player
    - People, June 15, 1992 (Box MLM 18, Item 2)
      Brief mention of William gaines' death
    - People, January 24, 2000 (Box MLM 18, Item 3)
    - Picture Week, "This Story is MAD", August 27, 1955 (Box MLM 18, Item 4)
      Early introductory article about MAD
    - Picture Week, "Slow Motion", January 17, 1956 (Box MLM 18, Item 5)
      Article about "Inside MAD" paperback